<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://HANXU2018.github.io</id>
    <title>HANXU2018 blog</title>
    <updated>2020-05-07T03:04:07.617Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://HANXU2018.github.io"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://HANXU2018.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>Han xu&apos;s personal blog</subtitle>
    <logo>https://HANXU2018.github.io/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://HANXU2018.github.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2020, HANXU2018 blog</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[AboutMe]]></title>
        <id>https://HANXU2018.github.io/post/about/</id>
        <link href="https://HANXU2018.github.io/post/about/">
        </link>
        <updated>2020-05-07T02:33:33.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My name is han xu. I am a student of hebei university in China.Is an information security sophomore undergraduate (as of May 2020).<br>
I'm interested in the open source culture of the github community.<br>
In order to record my learning process, I started this blog.<br>
I like to use LeetCode for code practice every day. At present, I mainly study the background development knowledge of Java.<br>
I taught myself basic C++ syntax to learn data structures<br>
I have learned C language and python language in school courses and have a little understanding of js<br>
Currently studying database courses, MySQL is the database environment I am using.<br>
Participated in the small program cloud development evangelist activity held by tencent community, tried to develop a simple serverless WeChat small program.<br>
Currently, I use lenovo Y700P to run win10 for daily learning, but I am interested in the cool and free Linux desktop environment.<br>
I tried to install arch on ubuntu18.04 desktop but failed. Manjaro felt that it was suitable for me, but I finally gave up due to incompatible hardware conditions.<br>
In a word, I have tried a lot of computer technology, but I don't have a deep understanding of it, which is both my weakness and my strength.<br>
I am curious about new technologies and interested in open source culture. I have been involved in programming for less than two years and my technical foundation is still very weak and there is still a long way to go.I look forward to seeing everyone here continue to learn with me and keep exploring and pursuing the future.<br>
This is the first time to write a blog in English. If you have any questions, please forgive me.<br>
Your correction is welcome.<br>
Now I'm learning the springboot framework to develop front and rear split web pages<br>
Please feel free to contact me if you have any questions<br>
My github is @HANXU2018<br>
My Chinese blog site https://hanxu.blog.csdn.net/<br>
email h1076998404@Gmial.com<br>
QQ mailbox can get my reply faster 1076998404@qq.com<br>
thanks<br>
2020/5/7</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>